<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content"><channel><title>Weissazool Dot Com</title><description>Dusting off my little corner of the internet</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 11:16:10 +0900</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 11:16:10 +0900</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-06-28sotd</guid><title>Jōkakuji</title><description>Welcoming jizō, Apr 29, 2020</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-06-28sotd</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 10:40:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/jokakuji.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/jokakuji.jpeg"
  alt="A row of jizō welcome guests to the temple"/>
  <figcaption>The statues offer their hospitality.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Jōkakuji</h1><p>This temple is tucked away on Yasukuni avenue. I don't know how many dozens of times I've passed on it before even noticing it, much less actually taken the time to stop and have a look. It almost feels like someone's cottage hidden at the back of a garden path, which is... unusual, to say the least, for Shinjuku. The hortensias must be in bloom right now. I should stop by again.</p><p>Speaking of flowering plants, I picked up an app that you can use to take a photo of a flower - and then it identifies the plant for you.</p><p>First of all, that's amazing, technologically, partly because at this point it's <em>not</em> amazing anymore. We are beginning to take for granted that there will be some service or app that can identify things for you based on images. A friend and I were trying to figure out what some flowers were as we were walking around Ueno park, and I thought, gee, I wonder if there's an app for that? Yes, yes there is. (I tried PictureThis.)</p><p>More importantly, I recognized most of the names of the flowers we saw. But I had never been able to associate an image with that name. I hope I will remember and have clearer images of a scene in my mind when someone writes about dogwoods or mallow in novels. I feel like people have practically no botanical knowledge with which to frame their imagination when reading them as words in a book. Coincidentally, I'm reading a book called Overstory with some friends, in which plants play a major role, so... the timing is good.</p><p><a href="./../../sotd/lantana.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/lantana.jpeg"
  alt="Lantana flowers"/>
  <figcaption>The thing is, I don't remember seeing any of these on Lantana Road...</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><p>Just yesterday, I was walking around Daikanyama and used the app to identify a flower. Turns out they're called "lantana." Which is the name of a road near where I lived as a child. I never stopped to think about where that road's name came from before - it was just simply the name of the road. So, turns out it's a plant. Native to the southeast US, so I don't know what the hell it's doing here. I'd be pleased to feel the little touch of home, especially since it's not like I can go there right now, only, well, it's an invasive species. So it goes.</p><p>Oh, and following up on Kinoene soy sauce. I couldn't find any in the supermarket. Maybe it's not actually a thing?</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-06-21-sotd</guid><title>Sensōji</title><description>Twilight at Kaminarimon, May 31, 2020</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-06-21-sotd</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 18:51:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/sensoji-kaminarimon.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/sensoji-kaminarimon.jpeg"
  alt="One of the entrances to Sensoji, Kaminarimon"/>
  <figcaption>It's so quiet without all the tourists.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Sensōji</h1><p>I wandered over to Asakusa shortly after the state of emergency was lifted for some yakitori and a drink. Also went by a cool wine bar, which served only Japanese wine. The wine was OK (which is high praise for Japanese wine), but the bar itself was pretty sweet.</p><p>It's shocking to be able to wander up and down Sensōji, particularly the shopping arcade, without it being absolutely swamped by people. I could have gotten an even quieter shot of Kaminarimon, but I just took this quickly in passing.</p><p>A fun moment in learning Japanese, way back when: I didn't realize it until I saw the signage in Asakusa station for the first time, but "Asakusa" and "Sensō" are two different readings of the same characters.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-06-14-sotd</guid><title>Daikoku-jinja</title><description>Kinoene soy sauce, Jun 6, 2020</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-06-14-sotd</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 10:59:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/kinoene.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/kinoene.jpeg"
  alt="A lamp post advertising Kinoene soy sauce."/>
  <figcaption>Caption</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1><a href="http://www.daikokujinja.org">Daikoku-jinja</a></h1><p>For some reason there are a few incredibly old lamp posts advertising a brand of soysauce that I think doesn't really sell internationally. I've seen it in supermarkets but never bought it. Guess I'll try it next time.</p><p>The kanji for it is 甲子, which is actually a word, rather than a name, although it can be used in names. "First of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexagenary_cycle">sexagenary cycle</a>." If you don't want to dig into that, think Chinese zodiac. So this shrine has a festival for it which occurs every 60 days.</p><p>Why a soysauce company would name itself that... I thought it might be something clever to do with the the year the company was founded (1830), but no, the closest years of the cycle are 1804 and 1864. According to the <a href="https://kinoene.com/company/">company website</a>, they chose the name based on its significance in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Onmyōdō">Onmyōdō</a> - "first," and "rare."</p><p>Anyway, I ran across this shrine because I went to Komagome for the first time ever. The Kyu-Furakawa gardens were closed, so I was wandering along back streets towards a large cemetery when I passed by a guy playing with his little boy.</p><p>"Oh wait, I know that guy," I realized a moment later.</p><p>Turned out my completely arbitrary path had taken me right past their house. Ah, serendipity.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-30</guid><title>Finally deployed!</title><description>Houston, we have liftoff</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-30</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 12:23:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../working-hard.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../working-hard.jpeg"
  alt="Working from hammock"/>
  <figcaption>Of course WFH stands for Working From Hammock. What else would it be?</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Finally deployed!</h1><p>Well, this is now available in a public space. Not that anyone will bother reading it. That said, I subscribe to friends' (very infrequently updated) blogs via RSS and read everything they post. That's actually my preferred way of keeping up with people... because social media is terrible.</p><p>That said, the RSS feed doesn't seem to be working very well at the moment. I'll get to it eventually, if anyone actually complains to me about it. My first priority though is to improve the design (CSS, eek) first in order to make this look a bit less generic.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-29-sotd</guid><title>Shrine at the Hotel Grand Mer Sankaiso</title><description>Hatsumoude, Jan 1, 2020</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-29-sotd</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:25:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/grand-mer.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/grand-mer.jpeg"
  alt="A shrine on the field behind the hotel"/>
  <figcaption>The wind was so strong I nearly couldn't get back into the hotel after hatsumoude.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Shrine at the <a href="https://www.hotel-grandmer.com">Hotel Grand Mer Sankaiso</a></h1><p>Context: Road trip up to Aomori to stay in a cabin and watch the snow fall.</p><p>After marinating in the cabin for a few days we decided to go to an onsen and marinate in some nice hot water for a change. The incredibly patient K (the only person with a license out of our group of six, despite the fact that we were going on a <em>road trip</em>) drove us over to a nearby onsen hotel with a view overlooking the ocean.</p><p>It was incredibly windy, to the point where the people at the hotel informed us that we wouldn't be able to use the outdoor baths. Fortunately that turned out to be more of a suggestion than a prohibition, which everyone ignored.</p><p>One excellent thing about expensive hotels in Japan is that they generally also sell access to their onsen for less than ¥1000. I wonder if it's a loss leader, and they expect to make it up in people sticking around for their restaurant or gift shops. Or even for an onsen customer to come back sometime for a hotel stay.</p><p>The wind really was howling outside. But there was a peculiar joy to staring out into the dark, hearing the roar of the ocean and the howl of the wind, shifting in and out of the hot water to adjust from one extreme temperature to the next.</p><p>Anyway, after the bath, I had a few moments to explore the hotel lobby and I noticed this small shrine outside. Since it was the new year, it seemed like a good opportunity for <em>hatsumoude</em>.</p><p>Under the ocean's roar, I whispered my wishes for 2020. What I wished for, I couldn't tell you now - my memory has been washed away by the sound of those waves.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-25-sotd</guid><title>Tochoji</title><description>On the way to work, April 29, 2020</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-25-sotd</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 22:42:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/tochoji-graveyard.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/tochoji-graveyard.jpeg"
  alt="Sotoba behind Tochoji"/>
  <figcaption>Not giant popsicle sticks, no.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1><a href="https://www.tochoji.jp">Tochoji</a></h1><p>I needed to pick something up from the office. I think this was the first time I had been to the office in a month? Two? And I haven't been back since.</p><p>This temple has always caught my eye, because it seems so modern. One of the nice things about this project is that it's really gotten me to slow down and have a proper look at some of the things I'm passing by. I don't have the patience to walk everywhere a lá <a href="https://craigmod.com">Craig Mod</a>, but I've paused along my usual routes and finally poked my head into some of the interesting places along the way.</p><p>The temple is actually more modern than I thought. There is a weird tower across the street, which I would not have imagined was related. But apparently it's a meditation hall. I don't even have a picture of it, because I had no idea there was a connection.</p><p>I love walking through graveyards. On a windy day the wooden markers (<em>sotoba</em>) clack and rattle against each other. Aoyama-reien is a favorite of mine. There's always another corner to explore there. I think the connection I feel to graveyards here is because the rituals of care, of cleaning, decorating, and communing, feel so close to the rituals of care for the graves of my mother's family.</p><p>When I first moved to Japan, I would occasionally take a shortcut through a temple graveyard to shave a minute off of my fifteen-minute walk to work. It was my first summer here and I had to wear a suit every day. I didn't have any light suits, nor did I even really understand that there was such a thing as different suits for different seasons. I say this to try, and fail, to justify my reasons for shaving as much time off my walk as I could. Anyway, one day an elderly woman was there, taking care of her family grave, and she gave me The Look of Death, specifically the What The Hell Do You Think You're Doing Here You Damn Dirty Foreigner, and in this case she was absolutely right. That was enough to keep me from using that shortcut ever again.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-24-sotd</guid><title>Mizuinari-jinja</title><description>After beer trading, May 2, 2020</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-24-sotd</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 10:22:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/mizuinari-jinja-lantern.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/mizuinari-jinja-lantern.jpeg"
  alt="Paper lantern at Mizuinari-jinja"/>
  <figcaption>Paper lanterns are the best lanterns. Everybody knows this.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Mizuinari-jinja</h1><p>During my extensive research, AKA skimming <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/水稲荷神社">the wikipedia page</a>, it seems that:</p><p>This shrine is really old. (Circa 941 😱)</p><p>It used to be somewhere which is now the Waseda campus. (It's now across the street from it.)</p><p>I was imagining that Waseda had some connection to the shrine, because Waseda (早稲田) contains one of the same kanji as inari (稲荷). Long story short, no, not beyond the fact that both things are related to the harvest, like just about everything else. Waseda used to be the cow place, next to the high horse place, but then it got renamed to the early rice place. 🤷🏻‍♂️</p><p><a href="https://kyotobrewing.com/">Kyoto Brewing Company is delivering six-packs of good craft beer for reasonable prices.</a> By "reasonable prices," I mean that it's cheaper than buying craft beer at a bar, if going to a bar and purchasing a craft beer was actually a thing you could do. Their selection seems to be changing quite frequently, which is great if what you like is variety. Since I like variety, I negotiated a trade with a co-worker who had bought a different six-pack. A couple of my 春の気まぐれ (a pale ale) for a couple of his 夜空を藍染め (a berry sour).</p><p><a href="./../../sotd/mizuinari-jinja.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/mizuinari-jinja.jpeg"
  alt="The main building at Mizuinari-jinja"/>
  <figcaption>The guardians are not impressed by your "what does the fox say?" joke. They've already heard it a million times.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><p>We attempted to conduct the trade in a socially distanced manner. We handed the beers off, one by one, in order to stay at arms' length, awkwardly stretching our hands as far away from our vulnerable orifices as we could. Now that I think about it, we could have set the beers on the ground in a neutral zone and then retrieved the beers. Like we were trying to set up some exchange in which neither could double-cross the other and try and grab all the goods for themselves.</p><p>It's been a few weeks since the trade and neither of us is dead. We can employ more advanced strategies next time, I guess.</p><p>On the way back from this exchange, I stopped by this shrine, which I had never bothered to investigate when I was at Waseda. Fox (inari) shrines tend to be just a small altar off to the side of another, larger shrine, so I like seeing them stand on their own.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-17-sotd</guid><title>Sousenji</title><description>On the way home from the Arakawa, May 16, 2020</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-17-sotd</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 08:29:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/sousenji-hill.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/sousenji-hill.jpeg"
  alt="Sousenji from behind"/>
  <figcaption>Perched atop a hill</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1><a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/総泉寺">Sousenji</a></h1><p>My planned workouts were done for the week. But I had started one of those Apple Watch exercise competitions with a friend, and I was just barely ahead. I needed plenty of exercise to get my maximum points for the day and guarantee my win, but didn't really want to do anything high impact that would affect my workouts for the next week.</p><p>So I decided to take a bike ride along the Arakawa river. I'd ridden downstream once before, but never upstream. I was also secretly hoping to see some people throwing a frisbee around and get a few throws in myself, but no luck. Unsurprisingly.</p><p>On the way back, there was this incredibly imposing temple sitting at the very top of a hill.</p><p><a href="./../../sotd/sousenji-front.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/sousenji-front.jpeg"
  alt="One day I will learn what these round tower-type buildings are for."/>
  <figcaption>Perched atop a hill</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><p>It has a number of cool buildings and features, none of which I have any sort of vocabulary to describe appropriately. I linked to the wikipedia article for this temple, but it's a bit too dense for me to get through before work.</p><p>Oh, and my watch ran out of battery halfway through the ride. I ended up losing the competition.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-07</guid><title>Fuji Sunset</title><description>Fuji sunset, May 7, 2020</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-05-07</link><pubDate>Thu, 7 May 2020 22:30:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../fuji-sunset.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../fuji-sunset.jpeg"
  alt="Fuji sunset"/>
  <figcaption>A beautiful sunset at the end of a beautiful day</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Fuji Sunset</h1><p>Spent a good chunk of the afternoon WFH (Working From Hammock) on the forbidden part of the roof so I could keep an eye on Fuji. You know, to make sure it didn't go anywhere or anything.</p><p>It's hard to get a good photo of Fuji during the day. It just fades into the blue of the sky and the white of the clouds. Even when I know it's there, I question my sanity.</p><blockquote><p>Is that really Fuji? Or just a cloud? It's way higher than all those other mountains...</p></blockquote><p>Then on the clearest of days, or at sunset, I am reminded: Fuji is way higher than all those other mountains.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/projects/stay-home-hanami-2020</guid><title>Stay Home Hanami 2020</title><description>The cherry blossoms next door</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/projects/stay-home-hanami-2020</link><pubDate>Sun, 3 May 2020 14:35:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Stay Home Hanami 2020</h1><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u256BZYYdbs" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>I took a photo of the sakura tree next door every day for a month.</p><p>I've been doing this for a few years now, although I usually would miss days here and there. This has been the most consistent year so far. It probably worked out this year because I was just at home the whole time, and this would give me at least some reason to step outside for a bit.</p><p>I decided to try putting together all the live photo videos. The quality is... not high, but you can still see the transformation. I think there are a couple of issues - the live photos themselves are not as high quality as the photos themselves, plus, it seems like a lot of compression happened between exporting the video and uploading it to Youtube.</p><p>Maybe one year I'll do a time-lapse video... who knows.</p><p>It was fun to mess around with iMovie again. I actually have another project I'd like to do with that. We'll see how it goes.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-28-sotd</guid><title>Zenjo-in</title><description>Passing by on a bicycle, April 4, 2020.</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-28-sotd</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 23:21:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/zenjo-in.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/zenjo-in.jpeg"
  alt="Zenjo-in"/>
  <figcaption>Looking at the map, this is part of a temple complex. I'll have to go back and explore further.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Zenjo-in</h1><p>I followed the Myōshōji river on its meandering way on my way to Heiwanomori park, looking for other possible green spaces to throw or train in.</p><p>I'm trying to half pay attention and participate in a drinking conversation with work colleagues while writing this. It's not working.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-24-sotd</guid><title>Tounji</title><description>A detour from a run, April 21, 2020.</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-24-sotd</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 21:29:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/tounji.jpeg"><figure>
<img src="./../../sotd/tounji.jpeg"
alt="Tounji"
/>
  <figcaption>Closed for the day, or for COVID-19.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Tounji</h1><p>This seems to be part of a complex of several temples, all of which have un (cloud, 雲) in their name. I've passed by the main temple many times before, but this was the first time I had realized that there were more temples behind it in back alleys.</p><p>There's this greenway which I've been walking up and down these days. Mostly to get out of the house and get some exercise. It used to be a river. Apparently, <a href="https://thetokyofiles.com/2016/01/17/walking-on-water-the-underground-rivers-of-tokyo/">there's a lot of smaller waterways that have been undergrounded in Tokyo</a>. I'd like to run it. I think it's probably about 3km long. But it has narrow pathways and steps and little playground areas, so I end up running along roads that parallel it instead. On one of those parallel roads, I came across the alley that led me here.</p><p>Writing this, I was listening to a binaural recording from <a href="https://walkkumano.com/iseji/">a site describing a weeklong hike in Mie</a> and felt a terrible longing for the sound and smell of waves.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-21-sotd</guid><title>Kumano-jinja</title><description>From a pedestrian overpass under a highway, April 19, 2020.</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-21-sotd</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 22:14:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/kumano-jinja.jpeg"><figure>
<img src="./../../sotd/kumano-jinja.jpeg"
alt="Kumano-jinja"
/>  
<figcaption>Industrial torii.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Kumano-jinja</h1><p>For these giant gateways, supplicants pass over, not through.</p><p>I'm curious. What might the cumulative value of the real estate of the shrines and temples in the Tokyo metropolitan area be? We could work out a rough estimate by average value of a square meter of land multiplied by the actual land area of the temples and shrines. I wonder if we could get a rough idea of what that land area was via some mapping API. Google's map API is now "Google Maps Platform" and has testimonials by Allstate, so that's right out. It seems like the <a href="https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Overpass_API">Overpass API for OpenStreetMap</a> could be useful though.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-20-sotd</guid><title>Tenso-jinja</title><description>On the way back from picking up some unorthodox building blocks, April 18, 2020.</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-20-sotd</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 21:29:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/tenso-jinja.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/tenso-jinja.jpeg"
  alt="Tenso-jinja">
  <figcaption>
  Are the inscribed names local community members? Priests? J-pop idols?
  </figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Tenso-jinja</h1><p>A few weeks earlier, the first time I was using my new weight lifting rack at home, I had forgotten the golden rule: do unto the weights on the left side of the barbell as you do unto the right. Gravity punished me for breaking the rule by shattering the wheels of my TV stand. Gravity was actually quite kind, since it could just as easily have broken the TV itself, or injured me.</p><p><a href="./../../sotd/wheels.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/wheels.jpeg"
  alt="Shattered caster wheels."/>
  <figcaption>The weird little head thing had been hiding underneath the TV stand for uncountable years.
  </figcaption>
</figure></a></p><p>Long story short, after trying out a few different fixes, I picked up some supplies to MacGyver the TV stand and popped in for a closer look at this shrine on the way back. 天祖 (the characters for "heaven" and "ancestor") is a relatively common name for a shrine. At least, it seems that way to me since there are a bunch of them on Google maps. The name seems to refer to the gods who are ancestors of the imperial line. Hopefully one day I'll dig in further than a cursory Google search. Another potential outcome for this project.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-16-sotd</guid><title>Yoyogi-Hachimangu</title><description>Finally exploring Yoyogi-Hachimangu, April 15, 2020.</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-16-sotd</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 23:17:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/yoyogi-hachimangu-1.jpeg"><figure>
<img src="./../../sotd/yoyogi-hachimangu-1.jpeg"
alt="Yoyogi-Hachimangu"
/>
  <figcaption>I had never ventured up these steps before.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Yoyogi-Hachimangu</h1><p>I've been up and down Yamate-dōri many, many times. But I have never stopped at any of the half a dozen or so intriguing shrines and temples along the way, until this day. Yoyogi-hachimangu has always interested me because you can't see the shrine from the street - just a torii at the top of the stairs.</p><p>I had had an inkling that there was a fair amount of space behind the torii, but was still suprised at just how much.</p><p>There was an exhibit of an ancient thatched house, which is incredibly difficult to imagine in Tokyo.</p><p><a href="./../../sotd/yoyogi-hachimangu-2.jpeg"><figure>
<img src="./../../sotd/yoyogi-hachimangu-2.jpeg"
alt="Purification station closed"/>
<figcaption>This water cannot cure COVID-19. Try bleach instead.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><p>Also of interest: the purifying water station (there's got to be a better way to express that) was closed due to the quarantine.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-15-sotd</guid><title>Sakuragaike Fudō-in</title><description>Snapped in passing, April 4, 2020.</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-15-sotd</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 22:15:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/sakuragaike-fudo-in.jpeg"><figure>
<img src="./../../sotd/sakuragaike-fudo-in.jpeg"
alt="Sakuragaike Fudō-in"
/>
  <figcaption>The more banners the better.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Sakuragaike Fudō-in</h1><p>That day I went to Heiwanomori to check on the grassy space there. They had cut down a lot of the trees and replaced them with a water feature and a turf field. Selfishly, I'm OK with the turf field. The field also had a couple of nets that I could throw a frisbee at... were they not completely monopolized by a bunch of kids playing soccer. Still, it seemed like a good place where I could do some solo throwing.</p><p>Too bad it was closed a few days later for the state of emergency.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-14-sotd</guid><title>経塚</title><description>A sutra mound snapped in passing on April 8, 2020.</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-14-sotd</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:14:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/kyoudzuka.jpeg"><figure>
<img src="./../../sotd/kyoudzuka.jpeg"
alt="Kyoudzuka"
/>
  <figcaption>I'm not sure what's weirder, the little table for two or the creature on the telephone pole.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>経塚</h1><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sutra_mound">きょうづか - a sutra mound</a>.</p><p>On <a href="./../projects/sotd">the project page</a> I noted that one of my goals with this is to force myself to dig back into my photo library and find pictures of shrines and temples, cleaning up and finding other gems along the way. Each post will take me further back in time.</p><p>Of course, if I take new photos of shrines or temples, I'll probably write about those first. I'm curious as to what the rhythm will be like. Will it be two steps down, one step out? You might imagine that during the quarantine, I would find fewer new shrines, but I disagree. I've found myself with far more leisure to wander down new alleys and pathways (though somehow still in a rush).</p><p>The other question I have is how many posts I might write a day. These feel like they'll be brief, so I could conceivably line up a few and take other days to dig into the meta-work of familiarizing myself with the tools for publishing and laying out this site. I've written two posts today, for example.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-13-sotd</guid><title>Hikawa-jinja</title><description>Snapped in passing on April 8, 2020.</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-13-sotd</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 21:14:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/hikawa-jinja.jpeg"><figure>
<img src="./../../sotd/hikawa-jinja.jpeg"
alt="Hikawa-jinja"
/>
  <figcaption>The main yearly festival for this shrine happens on the first Sunday of October.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Hikawa-jinja</h1><p>I passed by this one on the same ride as yesterday's post. The sign on the right side lists the shrine's yearly festivals.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/projects/sotd</guid><title>SOTD</title><description>Shrine of the day</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/projects/sotd</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 15:21:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>SOTD</h1><p>Shrine of the day. Which is a misnomer, since there may be temples as well. I am not distinguishing between 神社 and 寺 for this exercise.</p><p>If I can think of a better name, I'll update it. Daily Religious Structure is terrifying. Today's Temple sounds preachy. Ideas welcome.</p><p>Things this project gives me:</p><ul><li>Writing prompts.</li><li>Incentive to delve into and enjoy my backlog of photos while looking for source material.</li></ul>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-12-sotd</guid><title>Tofukuji</title><description>Snapped in passing on April 8, 2020.</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/blog/2020-04-12-sotd</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 15:12:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../sotd/tofukuji.jpeg"><figure>
  <img src="./../../sotd/tofukuji.jpeg"
  alt="Tofukuji"/>
  <figcaption>It's written right-to-left over the gate.</figcaption>
</figure></a></p><h1>Tofukuji</h1><p>I had a great plan to start work early in order to take a two-hour lunch break to get some solo throwing and agility training in. The previous weekend I had discovered that Heiwanomori park now has a turf multi-use field that is open to the public, with a few nets that I could throw into. Unfortunately, now that the state of emergency was in effect, that field was closed. They used to have a big grass field, but it's under renovation.</p><p>Frustrated and pressed for time, I found another park on the map and headed up to it in hopes of at least having some space to do my agility workout.</p><p>On the way, I passed by a couple of temples, of which this is one. I would have loved to explore a bit more, but I just took one shot of this gentleman walking in and moved on.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/projects/why</guid><title>Why</title><description>What's this site for?</description><link>https://weissazool.github.io/weissazool/projects/why</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 15:07:00 +0900</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Why</h1><p>Why does this site exist?</p><h2>Learning</h2><p>I used to play around with Jekyll to generate static sites from Markdown. I probably have a few public repositories of these here and there.</p><p>Unfortunately, it felt hard to justify time and effort working with Jekyll, since it was so different from what I did on a day-to-day basis. Although I must note that learning a templating tool (Liquid) has come in handy when using <a href="https://github.com/SwiftGen/SwiftGen">SwiftGen</a>. At any rate, generating static sites from Swift will allow me to play with something that is more relevant to what I want to be doing work-wise, so, two birds with one stone.</p><h2>Fun</h2><p>I miss writing!</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>